Guide to the Marilyn Horne Foundation Records, 1991-2011 CTC.2010.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Marilyn Horne Foundation Records
1991-2011
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Marilyn Horne Foundation
CTC.2010.01
66 Linear Feet (151 manuscript boxes)
The Marilyn Horne Foundation was formed in 1993 to promote the art of the vocal recital. Renowned mezzo soprano opera star Marilyn Horne wanted to support young recitalists and give them the opportunity to hone their craft. The records include financial information, artist information, board of trustee files, marketing materials, video and audio recordings, photographs, and posters.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Marilyn Horne Foundation in 2010.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection details the entire history of the Marilyn Horne Foundation and its efforts to promote young classical singers and the art of the vocal recital. The materials are arranged into four series: Office Files, Programs and Events, Photographs, and Audio/Visual Recordings. Included in the collection is information on the artists that performed for and were sponsored by the foundation; files on the development, marketing, and finances of the foundation; board of trustees meeting minutes; and a large amount of materials on the Foundation's education program in New York City and also its national residency program. The Foundation's two main productions, The Song Continues annual concert and the On Wings of Song recital program, are both covered in great detail.
History
The Marilyn Horne Foundation (MHF) was formed in 1993 to promote the art of the vocal recital. Marilyn Horne is widely recognized as one of the greatest opera performers in history. Ms. Horne started her foundation because she grew worried that the tradition of the song recital was disappearing. The eminent opera star wanted to support young recitalists and give them the opportunity to refine their craft. She acknowledged that there still seemed to be eager audiences for song recitals in cities like New York, but at the time, Ms. Horne noted that institutions and organizations around the country that used to present song recital series regularly started dropping out of the business.
The Marilyn Horne Foundation was one of the most influential and esteemed national nonprofits devoted exclusively to song and to gifted young vocal recitalists. The Foundation was officially launched on January 16, 1994, with a gala concert at Carnegie Hall celebrating Ms. Horne's 60th birthday. The mission statement of the Foundation was "to encourage, support and preserve the art of the vocal recital through the presentation of recitals and related educational activities in communities across the United States."
The Marilyn Horne Foundation achieved this mission through the presentation of recitals, residencies, concerts, radio broadcasts, educational outreach and song commissions. In addition to performances at Carnegie Hall and the Julliard School of Music, the Foundation performed hundreds of recitals at schools, colleges, and universities across the country. The Foundation sponsored "The Song Continues," which was a weeklong festival of master classes and recitals culminating with an annual concert.
The Foundation selected a number of aspiring young singers to send on the road for four-day residencies in partnership with community-based concert presenters, music festivals or colleges. The singers offered recitals and visited local schools. The first two singers sponsored by the Foundation were soprano Bridgett Hooks and tenor Olafur Bjarnason. There was also a competition, held in July for students enrolled at the Music Academy for the West in Santa Barbara, California, where Marilyn Horne served as a voice program director from 1977. Two winners (a singer and pianist) were presented each season at the "Wings of Song" recital in New York.
The Foundation also supported the "On Wings of Song" program which started in 1995 as a vocal recital series and later included radio broadcasts on WQXR. Marilyn Horne and WQXR's Elliot Forrest co-hosted an hour that consisted of part concert, part master-class, and part reminiscence. The concerts were recorded live at Christ & Stephen's Church in New York City. The program was eventually folded into "The Song Continues" series.
Over the course of the fifteen year plus history of the Foundation, over 100 artists were sponsored. In July 2010, the Foundation closed and the programs of the Marilyn Horne Foundation were incorporated into the Weill Music Institute at Carnegie Hall with Marilyn Horne serving as the Artistic Advisor. Both The Song Continues, the annual festival, and the On Wings of Song vocal recital series live on to introduce and support emerging young vocalists.
Arrangement
The records of the Marilyn Horne Foundation are organized into five series:
Series I. Office Files, 1991-2010
Series II. Programs and Events, 1993-2011
Series III. Photographs, 1994-2009
Series IV. Audio/Visual Recordings, 1995-2010
Series V. Posters, 1998-2008
Previous Citation
Marilyn Horne Foundation Records, 1991-2011, CTC.2010.01, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Photographs; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- New York (State) -- New York; Endowments -- New York (State) -- New York; Music; Pianists -- New York (State) -- New York; Associations; Singers -- New York (State) -- New York; Concerts -- New York (State) -- New York; Music -- Performance -- New York (State) -- New York; Vocal music -- Study and teaching -- New York (State) -- New York; Video recordings (physical artifacts); Marilyn Horne Foundation; Horne, Marilyn
- Office Files, 1991-2010; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains the office files of the Marilyn Horne Foundation. It is divided into eight subseries containing materials on the artists who performed for the foundation, Board of Trustees meetings, development files, budget and financial materials, general office files, marketing files, and finally there are two subseries on the numerous residency programs that the foundation sponsored nationally and in the New York City area. Some of these subseries are broken down into smaller sections.
  - Artists, 1991-2010; 1.
    The Artists subseries is divided into two sections: Pianists and Vocal Artists. Each contains folders for individual performers that were contracted for performance by the Marilyn Horne Foundation and includes contracts, programs, photographs, newspaper clippings, and correspondence. The folders are arranged alphabetically by the artist's last name.
    - Pianists, 1994-2009
      - Pianists, 1994-2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Carol Anderson, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Thomas Bagwell, 1996-2005 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Michael Baitzer, 2000-2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Steven Blier (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Richard Carsey, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Jocelyn Dueck, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Mikael Eliasen (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Brian Ferrell, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Douglas Fisher (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Margo Garrett (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Israel Gursky, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Miah Im, 2001-2004 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Ines Irawati (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Carol Isaac, 1999-2002 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Graham Johnson, 2004-2007 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Warren Jones, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Martin Katz, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Craig Ketter (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Phillip Kirchmann, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Victoria Kirsch (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Ji Young Lee (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - James Levine (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Donna Loewy, 2000-2004 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Carrie-Ann Matheson, 2001-2006 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - David Moody, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Kenneth Merrill (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Kevin Murphy, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Spencer Myer, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Djordje Stevan Nesic (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - J.J. Penna, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Steven Philcox, 2001-2004 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Svetlana Rodionova (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Craig Rutenberg, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Nino Sanikidze, 2001-2003 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Tamara Sanikidze, 2006-2009 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Speranza Scappucci (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Kate Stevens, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Jerome Tan, 2006-2009 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Craig Terry (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Laura Ward, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Howard Watkins, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Carol Wong, 2003-2006 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Brian Zeger, 1997-2004 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Vocal Artists, 1991-2010
      - Hanan Alattar, 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Keri Alkema, 2002-2004 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Elaine Alvarez, 2005-2007 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Jennifer Aylmer, 2000-2006 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Jason Baldwin - Audition, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Robert Baksa - Audition, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Isabel Bayrakdarian, 1998-2001 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Serena Benedetti - Audition, 2001-2004 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Jonathan Beyer, November 3, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Olafur Bjarnason (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Stephanie Blythe, 1997-2002 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Jesse Blumberg, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Russell Bruan, 1996-2001 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Lawrence Brownlee, 2001-2007 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Nicole Cabell, 2004-2005 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Leonardo Capalbo, 2004-2005 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Fred Carama - Jane Scovell grant, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Charles Castronovo, 1998-2002 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Jennifer Check, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Troy Cook, 1999-2003 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Sasha Cooke, 2006-2008 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - Richard Cox, 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - Maija Lisa Currie - Audition, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 23)
        - Demo recording, July 10, 2005; CD, 46 minutes
      - Eric Cutler, 2001-2003 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - David Daniels, 1996-2003 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - Julie Davis-Ramsey - Jane Scovell grant, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - Marcus DeLoach, 1997-2007 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - Michelle DeYoung, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - Ramone Diggs, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - Deborah Domanski, 2002-2005 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - Dean Ely, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Timothy Fallon, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Liesel Fedkenheuer, 1999-2002 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - William Ferguson, 2001-2006 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Renée Fleming, 1995-2008 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Bruce Ford, 1995-1999 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Nmon Ford, 2002-2005 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Andrew Garland, 2003-2008 (Box 4, Folder 8)
        - Demo recording, February 18, 2005; CD, 48 minutes
      - Rodney Gilfry, 1992-1999 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Ian Greenlaw, 2004-2006 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Jill Grove, 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Sari Gruber, 1996-2008 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Jerry Hadley, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Thomas Hampson, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Jason Hardy, 2004-2007 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Wendy Bryn Harmer, 2004-2009 (Box 4, Folder 16)
        - Demo recording, February 2008; CD, 41 minutes
      - Nicole Heaston, 1997-2005 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Scott Hendricks, 1998-2002 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Wendy Hoffman, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Bridgett Hooks, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Joshua Hopkins, 2002-2006 (Box 4, Folder 21)
        - Demo recording, CD, 30 minutes
      - Lisa Hopkins, 2003-2004 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Weston Hurt, 2003-2006 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Nicolai Janitzky, 2000-2005 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Georgia Jarman, 2005-2006 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Jane Jennings, 1997-2000 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Jessica Jones, 2002-2004 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Quinn Kelsey, 2003-2007 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Valerie Komar - Audition, 2001-2004 (Box 5, Folder 8)
        - Demo recording, May 9, 2004; CD, 29 minutes
        - Demo recording, 2001-2004; CD, 34 minutes
      - Dina Kuznetsova, 2000-2004 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Megan Latham, 2002-2005 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Margaret Lattimore, 1996-2003 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Brian Leerhuber, 1999-2001 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Daniela Lehner, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Marie Lenormand, 2001-2004 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Isabel Leonard, 2004-2006 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Shieh-Yih Lim, 1997-2001 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Frank Lopardo, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Lester Lynch, 1997-2005 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Amanda Majeski, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Olga Makarina, 1996-1998 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Karita Mattila, 2001-2003 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - John Matz, 2000-2003 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Monique McDonald, 1995-2004 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Bejun Mehta, 1998-2002 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Nikola Mijalovic, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Megan Miller, 1998-2002 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Megan Monaghan - Audition, 1995-2005 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Tamara Mumford (Box 6, Folder 10)
        - Demo recording, 2007; CD, 26 minutes
      - Heidi Grant Murphy, 1992-1998 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Dae San No, 1998-2004 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Christopheren Nomura, 1992-1997 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Simon O'Neill, 2001-2008 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - John Osborn, 1997-1999 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Simone Osborne - Visa application, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Sidney Outlaw, 2006-2007 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Pamela Pantos, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - René Pape, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Earle Patriarco, 1994-1996 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Nicholas Phan, 2004-2008 (Box 6, Folder 21)
        - Demo recording, CD, 12 minutes
        - Demo recording, CD, 14 minutes
      - Keith Phares, 2001-2004 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - Mary Phillips, 1996-2001 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Susanna Phillips, 2002-2009 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Dimitri Pittas, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 1)
        - Demo recording, April 18, 2006; CD, 68 minutes
      - Justin Plank, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Lee Poulis, 2000-2006 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Barbara Quintiliani, 2001-2006 (Box 7, Folder 4)
        - Demo recording, February 27, 2000; CD, 14 minutes
      - Brenda Rae, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Samuel Ramey, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Alex Richardson, 2002-2009 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Jennifer Rivera, 1997-2003 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Kenneth Roberson, 1996-2004 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Twyla Robinson, 2002-2006 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Katherine Rohrer, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Joslin Romphf, 2001-2006 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Joslin Romphf - Visa application, 1996-2006 (Box 7, Folder 13-14)
      - Yves Saelens, 1998-2001 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Anne-Marie Seager, 1997-2005 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Denis Sedov, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Rinat Shaham, 1997-2005 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Lauren Skuce, 2002-2005 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Bruce Sledge, 2001-2003 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Garrett Sorenson, 2004-2006 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Joshua Stewart - Grant, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Erica Strauss, 2002-2006 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Ruth Ann Swenson, 2000-2001 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Lynette Tapia, 1997-2000 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Charles Taylor, 2003-2005 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Bryn Terfel, 1997-2003 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Jessica Tivens, 1999-2001 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Gregory Turay, 1996-2000 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Benita Valente, 1997-2005 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Deborah Voigt, 1996-2004 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Frederica Von Stade, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Erin Wall, 2003-2005 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Ashley Watkins - Housing grant, 2007-2010 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Nathaniel Webster, 1998-2005 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Daniel Weeks, 1999-2004 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Erik Nelson Werner, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - James Westman, 1997-2003 (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - Avid Williams - Audition, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - Janet Williams, 1996-1998 (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - Leon Williams, 1991-1994 (Box 8, Folder 25)
      - Sarah Wolfson - Audition, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 26)
      - Erin Wood, 2000-2001 (Box 8, Folder 27)
      - Monica Yunus, 1999-2006 (Box 8, Folder 28)
      - Guang Yang, 2000-2004 (Box 8, Folder 29)
      - Dolora Zajick, 1997-1999 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Board of Trustees, 1994-2010; 2.
    This subseries contains the files that pertain to the Marilyn Horne Foundation's Board of Trustees. The subseries is split into two sections containing general files about the Board and its' members and the meeting minutes of the Board throughout its' existence. The Board of Trustee files are filed in alphabetical order by folder title and the meeting minutes are filed in chronological order.
    - Board of Trustee Files, 1994-2009
      - Artistic committee meetings, 1997-2007 (Box 9, Folder 1-20)
      - Artistic committee memos, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 21)
      - Artistic committee proposals, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - Board committees, 1996-1998 (Box 9, Folder 23)
      - Board evaluation, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - Board members, 1996-2000 (Box 9, Folder 25)
      - Board memos, 1994-2009 (Box 10, Folder 1-4)
      - Board requests, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Board responsibilities, 1997-2001 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Board terms of office and occupations, 1996-2008 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Conflict of interest policy, 2005-2008 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Executive committee, 1994-2004 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Executive committee meetings, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Finance committee, 1996-2005 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Nominating committee, January 31, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Organizational structure, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Planned giving committee, 2004-2005 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Board of Trustees Meeting Minutes, 1994-2010
      - Board of directors and officers minutes, November 4, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Telephone meeting of the board of directors minutes, February 24, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Board meeting minutes, April 6, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Board meeting minutes, October 24, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Board meeting minutes, February 8, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Board meeting minutes, September 23, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Annual meeting of the Board of Trustees minutes, May-June, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 7-8)
      - Board meeting minutes, October 28, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Board meeting minutes, February 17, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Annual meeting of the Board of Trustees minutes, May 11, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Board meeting minutes, October 15, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Board meeting minutes, February 5, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Annual meeting of the Board of Trustees minutes, May 14, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Board meeting minutes, October 15, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Board meeting minutes, February 14, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Annual meeting of the Board of Trustees minutes, April 10, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Board meeting minutes, October 13, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Board meeting minutes, February 2, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Annual meeting of the Board of Trustees minutes, May 3, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Board meeting minutes, October 29, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Board meeting minutes, March 1, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Annual meeting of the Board of Trustees minutes, May 13, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Artistic Committee meeting minutes, June 7, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Board meeting minutes, October 7, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Special fundraising meeting minutes, December 9, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Board meeting minutes, January 18, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Annual meeting of the Board of Trustees minutes, May 5, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - Board meeting minutes, October 20, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Board meeting minutes, February 2, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - Annual meeting of the Board of Trustees minutes, May 3, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - Board meeting minutes, October 12, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Board meeting minutes, January 31, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Annual meeting of the Board of Trustees minutes, May 2, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - Board meeting minutes, October 31, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Board meeting minutes, February 22, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Annual meeting of the Board of Trustees minutes, May 8, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Board meeting minutes, October 11, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Board meeting minutes, February 26, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Annual meeting of the Board of Trustees minutes, May 7, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Board meeting minutes, October 29, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Board meeting minutes, February 20, 2008 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Annual meeting of the Board of Trustees minutes, May 4, 2008 (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Board meeting minutes, October 6, 2008 (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - Board meeting minutes, January 19, 2009 (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - Annual meeting of the Board of Trustees minutes, May 4, 2009 (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Board meeting minutes, October 13, 2009 (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - Annual meeting of the Board of Trustees minutes, May 3, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Development, 1993-2010; 3.
    The Development subseries includes materials on the various organizations that granted and donated funds to the Marilyn Horne Foundation. Two of the major contributing groups were the National Endowment for the Arts and the New York State Council on the Arts. Included are correspondence, grant applications, reports, and other materials.
    - Annual campaign appeals, 1995-2006 (Box 14, Folder 1-8)
    - Annual campaign appeals, 2006-2009 (Box 15, Folder 1-4)
    - Corporation and foundation donations, 1993-1994 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Grants and residencies - Reports and data, 1998-2009 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Lower Manhattan Cultural Council, 2007-2008 (Box 15, Folder 7-8)
    - Membership campaign - Opera News ad, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - National Endowment for the Arts - Grant applications for FY03-04, 2002-2004 (Box 15, Folder 10-11)
    - National Endowment for the Arts - Grant application for FY05, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
    - National Endowment for the Arts - Grant application for FY06, 2005-2007 (Box 16, Folder 3-6)
    - National Endowment for the Arts - Grant application for FY07, 2006-2008 (Box 16, Folder 7-10)
    - National Endowment for the Arts - Grant application for FY08, 2007-2009 (Box 16, Folder 11-13)
    - National Endowment for the Arts - Grant application for FY09, 2008-2009 (Box 17, Folder 1-3)
    - National Endowment for the Arts - Grant application for FY10, 2009 (Box 17, Folder 4-5)
    - National Endowment for the Arts - History, 2003-2009 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - National Endowment for the Arts - Reports, 2006-2010 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - New York City Department of Cultural Affairs, 2000-2002 (Box 17, Folder 8-9)
    - New York City Department of Cultural Affairs, 2002-2004 (Box 18, Folder 1-3)
    - New York City Department of Cultural Affairs, 2004-2010 (Box 19, Folder 1-6)
    - New York State Council on the Arts - Applications, 2008-2009 (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
    - New York State Council on the Arts - Final reports, 1998-2003 (Box 20, Folder 3-9)
    - New York State Council on the Arts - Final reports, 2003-2006 (Box 21, Folder 1-6)
    - New York State Council on the Arts - Grant contract, 2009 (Box 21, Folder 7)